PAOLO ALBERTO DR. VELASCO

32 years old, Married

Phone: +63 917 800-2095; Email: paolov1ph@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://paolov1ph.github.io/portfolio/

OBJECTIVE

I aim to grow my IT career in a well-established organization that will fully utilize my team management, supervision and technical skills for mutual growth and success. I firmly believe that my 9-year working experience in actuarial valuation, pension administration and systems and program development will significantly contribute to your company's vision and mission.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Willis Towers Watson, Global Processing and Technology Center

IT Business Analyst – Tester & Quality Assurance, 2017 to 2018

- Creates testing plans for company in-house system for data management.
- Identifies points of improvement for company systems and tools.
- Provide system support for the global health and group benefits configuration team.

Pension Administration – Team Leader & Developer, 2014 to 2017

- Managed Philippine-based developer support team for United States Pension Administration Group.
- Developed programs for company systems for pension administration, calculations and forms
- Developed Bulk Lump Sum (BLS) and Pension Plan termination projects for United States
- Supervised the updating of employee databases to meet service level agreements for American and Canadian clients
- Provided programming set-up and support database updates for company in-house systems

<u>Major Accomplishment:</u> Played a key role in the creation & set-up of a new team by developing and implementing BLS processes & procedures, defining manpower requirements, hiring & actual operational start.

Actuarial Valuation - Actuarial Analyst, 2009 to 2014

- Performed accounting & funding valuations & projections for Defined Benefit (DB) & hybrid pension plans
- Provided programming set-up and support for pension plans for company in-house systems
- Provided administrative support for Defined Contribution (DC) benefit calculation
- Managed and supervised group plan valuations and benefit calculation projects

CERTIFICATION/EDUCATION/TRAININGS

Java 1 & 2 University of the Philippines, Diliman, ITDC 2018

Web Development Tuitt Coding Bootcamp, Quezon City

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

College University of Santo Tomas Manila, College of Science

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics Major in Actuarial Science, 2004-2008

Secondary & Primary Xavier High School, 2000-2004; Xavier Grade School, 1993-2000

PROFESSIONAL TRAININGS & SEMINARS

- 7 Habits for Managers; Towers Watson, Taguig City, Philippines; November 2016
- Project Management Training; Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia; July 2014
- Benefit Optimization: Building the right benefits programme for your organization; Towers Watson Regional Training, Shanghai, China; February 2013
- Benefits Design Training; Towers Watson Regional Training, Shanghai, China; February 2013
- 7 Habits of Highly Effective People; Towers Watson, Taguig City, Philippines 2012
- Assertive Communication; Towers Watson, Taguig City, Philippines; 2010

SKILLS

- Proficient in Web development and programming languages HTML, CSS, JS, PHP, MySQL, Java, jQuery, Visual Basic and Fortran.
- Proficient in Web development frameworks Bootstrap, MD Bootstrap, Materialize and Laravel.
- Proficient MS Office Applications.
- Excellent knowledge of pension and retirement plans in United States, Canada, Hong Kong, Korea, Taiwan, Sweden, and Philippines
- Excellent knowledge of pension accounting, financial mathematics and annuities
- Effective and efficient supervisory and management skills, people management and project management
- Excellent oral and written communication skills
- Solution-oriented, has good leadership and time management skills and best in finishing deadlines

